泰莎
Tessa.
我回来了
I'm home.
泰斯
Tess.
泰斯  你在吗
Tess, you here?
是你啊
Oh. It's you.
你以为是谁
Who'd you think it was?
不知道  我听到有动静
I don't know. I heard rustling.
你要用这个对抗歹徒吗
And you were gonna fight them off with that?
这个可以非常...
This could be very...
你回家做什么
What are you doing here?
我以为你下周末才回来
I thought you weren't coming till next weekend.
我得回来洗衣服  干净的穿完了
I had to do laundry. I ran out of clothes.
这么快吗  才两个星期
Already? It's only been two weeks.
不是说我不高兴见到你
Not that I'm not thrilled to see you,
可学校不是也有洗衣机吗
But don't they have washing machines on campus?
但是不好
They're not as nice.
你说不好  是指要钱吧
And by "Nice," you mean "Free."
-差不多  -就知道
- Pretty much. - Right.
对了  要买橙汁了
Uh, you're going to need more orange juice, by the way.
谢谢提醒
Thank you.
还有  冰淇淋也被我吃完了
Oh, and, um, I finished the ice cream... too.
你回来多久了
And... how long have you been here?
十分钟
Ten minutes.
反正你都回来了
Well, as long as you are here,
来个"吉它英雄"对抗赛怎么样
how about a guitar hero tournament?
我整个周末都在写作  需要休息下
I have been writing all weekend. I could use a break.
事实上  我得走了
Actually, I gotta go.
我要和朋友一起学习
I'm meeting some friends for a study session
已经迟到了
and I'm already late.
你不是要洗衣服吗
Uh, well, what about your laundry?
没事  晚点再洗
It's okay. I mean, I'll get it later.
-拜  爸  -拜
- Bye, dad. - Bye.
至少她有回家啊  对吧
I mean, she came home at least, right?
可我希望回来不只为了洗衣服和蹭东西吃嘛
Yeah, I just wish it was for more than laundry and supplies.
写作有进展吗
Did you get some writing done?
母亲大人不在  如有神助
With mother gone, are you kidding?
写了两章  不过得重写犯罪现场
Two chapters, but I gotta rewrite the crime scene.
现在写得太闷了
Right now it's boring.
也许这个能启发你  卡塞尔
Maybe this will inspire you, Castle.
相当让人毛骨悚然
Pretty damn freaky.
被害人叫泰莎·霍顿  29岁
Name's Tessa Horton, 29.
室友周末离开了  回到家后
Roommate came home from a weekend away,
发现她在上面
found her up there.
我的天
Ooh, jeez.
谁会把尸体挂在天花板上
Who puts a body on a ceiling?
我也不懂  不过我可能几周都睡不着了
Beats me, but I probably won't sleep for weeks.
感觉像是你书里才会有的情节  对吗
Looks like something out of one of your books, right?
死因呢
Cause of death?
勒痕与瘀点表示应该是被勒死的
Ligature marks and petechia suggest strangulation.
前额的伤口呢
What about this wound on her forehead?
不是致命的
Well, it's nonlethal.
从细节来看  应该是用剃刀割的
Given the detail, it looks like it was carved by some kind of razor.
好像是什么符号
It's a symbol of some kind.
你认识吗
Do you recognize it?
不  但凶手大费周章
No, but the killer went through a lot of trouble.
肯定有什么意义
It must mean something.
要挂起尸体不容易
It's not easy hanging a body,
她至少重100磅
and she's at least 100 pounds.
我跟鉴证组通了气
I checked in with C.S.U.
他们在走廊里发现了指纹
they found prints in the hallway,
但是公寓里却一尘不染
but the apartment is spotless.
看来被清洁过了
Looks like it's been wiped down.
这家伙在行凶后清洁过了
This guy cleaned up after himself.
他不介意慢慢来
He didn't mind taking his time.
所以凶手知道室友会离开市区
So the killer knew that the roommate was gonna be out of town.
这栋楼的安保情况怎么样
What's the security like in this place?
门铃在前门
Buzzer on the front door,
没有门卫和摄像头
no doorman or security cameras.
但没有强行闯入的迹象
But there's no sign of a forced entry,
没有打斗的痕迹
no sign of a struggle.
她认识凶手
She knew him.
好的  排查下邻近的公寓
All right, canvass neighboring apartments
看看有没有人看到或听到什么
for anyone that saw or heard anything,
我要知道这个符号是什么意思
And I want to know what this symbol means.
如果泰莎认识凶手
You know, if Tessa knew our killer,
她的室友可能会提供些情况
it's possible that her roommate could shed some light on all of this.
每次我闭上眼睛  都能见到她被挂在上面
Every time I close my eyes, I see her hanging there.
她做什么工作的
What did she do for a living?
她是商业房产的保险经纪人
She was an insurance broker for commercial real estate.
科茨曼保险公司
Kurtzman insurance.
她有很多朋友吗
Did she have a lot of friends?
她很内向
She was shy...
是个工作狂
and a workaholic.
我差不多要硬拽才能让她出门
I practically had to drag her out of the house.
没有男朋友吗
So no boyfriend then?
事实上  她开始谈恋爱了
Actually, she did start seeing someone,
大概六周前
maybe six weeks ago.
你知道是谁吗
Do you know who?
重点就是她只字未提  她...
That's the thing, she never did say. She...
她表现得好像是什么大秘密
She acted like it was some big secret,
就好像他结婚了还是怎么的
like maybe he was married or something.
但他送珠宝给她
But he bought her jewelry
带她去高级餐厅吃饭
and took her to these fancy dinners.
她说从没有人对她这样好过
She said no one's ever treated her that way before.
她还告诉你什么关于他的事了吗
Did she tell you anything else about him,
他长什么样子  在哪里认识的
The way he looked, where they met?
没有
No.
她只说他是每个女生的梦中情人
All she said was he was every woman's fairy tale--
富有  英俊  大方
Rich, handsome, and generous.
好狠的梦中情人
Well, some fairy tale.
我告诉你们  这事可不止和已婚男人
I'll tell you this much, there's a lot more to this story
发生婚外情那么简单
than an affair with a married man.
也许  但没找到他之前我们什么也不知道
Maybe, but we won't know what until we find him.
查她的通话记录  看看能不能找到这个人
Get on her phone records. See if you can I.D. this guy.
好  我还会叫他们查电邮
Yeah. I'll have 'em pull her e-mails, too.
符号有什么进展吗
Anything on that symbol yet?
问过联邦调查局了
Put a call into the feds.
他们现在正在查数据库
They're running it through their database right now.
怎么了
What?
他放置尸体的方式  所花的时间
The way he left the body, the time it took--
不管是谁做的
whoever did this,
他都很享受
He liked it.
如果她有男友  那晚并未发生什么事
If she had a boyfriend, nothing happened that night.
没有性暴力或性行为的痕迹
There are no signs of sexual assault or activity.
她是被勒死的
Death was by strangulation.
作案工具是绳子或者围巾
Looks like a rope or a scarf.
你能推测一下更准确的死亡时间吗
Were you able to narrow down a time?
周六凌晨2点到3点之间
Somewhere between 2:00 and 3:00 A.M. Saturday morning.
淤青和血迹表明凶手
Lividity and pooling indicate the body was hung
是在她死后将她挂上天花板的
from the ceiling postmortem.
为什么要在杀死她之后把尸体吊起来
Why would he hang her body after he killed her?
某种仪式吗
A ritual?
诡异的不止这些
That's not all that's weird.
勒杀是一种很暴力的行为
Strangulation is a violent act,
但她没有反抗的痕迹
But there were no signs that she fought back--
她的指甲中没有皮肤残留  没有瘀伤
No skin under the fingernails, no bruising--
所以我又做了些检查
So I did some checking.
她被下药了
She was drugged.
肺部组织显示她曾被氯仿麻醉过
Lung tissue suggests exposure to chloroform.
而且  凶手十分小心
Also... your killer was careful.
他作案时带着手套
He was wearing gloves.
你怎么知道的
How can you tell?
她的身体上残留有滑石粉
Traces of talcum powder on the body--
是那种手术手套上常用的滑石粉
The same talc used in surgical gloves
或是你们在犯罪现场取证用的手套
Or the evidence gloves that you use at the crime scenes.
不管凶手是谁
Whoever this person is,
都是一个十分专业的人
they knew exactly what they were doing.
他以前就干过这种事
He's done this before.
仪式型谋杀
Ritualistic killing,
能从中取乐
takes pleasure in it,
十分小心地处理犯罪现场
significant care exhibited at the crime scene...
都是连环杀手的显著特征
All the hallmarks of a serial killer.
是啊  但我从未见过这种作案模式
Yeah, but I've never seen this M.O.
嘿  坏消息
Hey, bad news.
联调局查了那个符号  没有结果
The feds struck out on the symbol.
它和古代的某种炼金术标志有些相似性
It bears some similarities to some ancient alchemy signs,
但他们之前从未见过这样的
but they've never seen this one before.
查电话记录有发现什么线索吗
Any luck on the phone records?
没有  但她曾经常
No, but she spent
和一个未知号码通话
a lot of time on the phone to a blocked number.
电话公司追查到
Phone company traced it
那是个未注册的一次性电话  用的是偷来的卡
to an unlisted burner phone with a stolen sim.
-说明他早有预谋  -是的
- So he planned ahead. - Yeah.
那她的邮件呢
What about her e-mails?
没有她那神秘男友的来信
Nothing from her mystery lover,
所以我让技术人员检查了一下她的硬盘
So I had them take a look at her hard drive.
发现有部分被彻底格式化了
Turns out portions of it have been surgically wiped,
像是某人要掩盖踪迹
like someone covering their tracks.
所以我们现在是一无所获了
So we're back to square one.
那可不一定
Not necessarily.
泰莎的室友说他曾给她一些珠宝
Uh, Tessa's roommate said that he gave her some jewelry.
或许他的指纹会残留在某件珠宝上
Maybe he left a fingerprint on one of those pieces.
我现在就去她家  看看能发现什么
I'll head to her place, see what I can find out.
珠宝  我肯定想不到这上面去的
Jewelry. I never would've thought of that.
恐怕等我生日快到的时候  得提醒你一下
I guess I'll have to remind you when my birthday's coming up.
怎么  贝克特警长
Why, detective Beckett,
你刚刚是故意给我留下了暗示吗
was that a hint you just dropped?
是的  卡塞尔先生  我觉得确实如此
Why, Mr. Castle, I do believe it was.
真可耻
Shameless.
贝克特  你有空吗
Yo, Beckett, you got a second?
我想跟你说句话
I need a word.
好吧  怎么
Okay. So...
什么事
What's up?
我拿到了鉴证组的鉴证结果
We got the C.S.U. Report back.
泰莎的公寓内部被清理得很干净
The inside of Tessa's apartment was wiped clean.
是啊  意料之中的事
Yeah, well, we expected that.
但我们没料想到这个
Yeah, but we didn't expect this.
鉴证组从外面的门把手和门框上
C.S.U. were able to pull prints off the outside doorknob
采集到一些指纹
and from around the door frame.
发现其中一组与泰莎和她室友的都不符
And they found a set that didn't match Tessa's or her roommate's.
当他们搜索的时候
When they ran it,
发现和系统中的另外一个人相匹配
they found a match to someone else in the system.
好吧  是谁
Okay. Who?
理查德·卡塞尔
Richard castle.
犯罪现场外采集的指纹样本
与理查德·卡塞尔相匹配
这..  不可能吧
Y--uh, that can't be right.
可能...  只是个意外吧
You know what? It w--it was probably just an accident.
他可能进门的时候不小心摸到了
He probably touched them on his way in
当时还没有戴上手套
before putting his gloves on.
是啊  那样倒也说得通
Yeah, I mean, that would explain it,
只不过鉴证组是在你们进去前先采样的
Except that C.S.U. Collected them before either of you arrived.
你确定吗
Are you sure about this?
你自己看吧  老兄
Look for yourself, bro.
卡塞尔  好好想想  有没有可能
Castle, think. Is it possible
是你进门的时候摸过门把手或者门框
that you touched the doorknob or the frame on your way in?
我进去的时候门是开着的  但我想我肯定摸过
It was open when I came in, but I guess I must have.
你以前去过那栋房子里吗
Had you been in that building before?
在今天之前都没去过
Not before today.
那个被害人呢
What about the victim?
你确定你不认识她吗
Are you sure you didn't know her?
哈维
Javi.
怎么
What?
你知道我必须得问
You know I have to ask.
不  事情很简单
No, it's simple, okay?
他进去的时候摸到了门
He touched the door when he walked in.
鉴证组搞错了采样时间
C.S.U. Got the time frame wrong.
那是唯一的解释
That's the only explanation.
除非我有个邪恶的双胞胎兄弟
Unless I've got an evil twin.
双胞胎的指纹是不一样的
Twins don't have the same fingerprints.
那是常见的错误想法  指纹就是你的
It's a common misconception. This was you.
是啊  我知道  我开玩笑罢了
Yeah, I know. I was joking.
犯罪现场被污染可不是玩笑
A contaminated crime scene is not a joke.
我去鉴证组那边说清楚一下
I'll square this away with C.S.U.
你下次管好你的手  好吗
You watch your hands next time, okay?
抱歉
Sorry.
下次小心点
Just be careful.
好的  好的
Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
我翻遍了泰莎的衣物
So I've been through all of Tessa's belongings.
没有名贵珠宝
No sign of any high-end jewelry,
不过从她的首饰盒中有几个空格推断
but from the empty spaces in her jewel box,
可能有几件首饰丢失
there might be some pieces missing.
他把送她的东西拿走了
He took back the ones he gave her.
好像他知道我们在找什么
It's like he knew what we were looking for.
这家伙清楚如何不露马脚
This guy really knows how to cover his tracks.
不  智者千虑  必有一失
Oh, no, not all of them.
我们彻查全楼后  发现有个邻居
Canvass of the building turned up a neighbor
他说看到有人在周五晚7:45
who claims he saw someone heading to her apartment
进了她的公寓
at 7:45 on Friday night.
这位邻居看清他的样子了吗
Did the neighbor get a good look at him?
他透过他家前门的猫眼
Well, he got a clear shot
看得一清二楚
right through his front door peephole.
我马上叫素描师来画像
I'm bringing in a sketch artist right now.
好  一画好就送过来
All right. Get it over as soon as it's done.
她室友说不定能认出来
The roommate might be able to I.D. him.
好的
You got it.
警探
Detective.
她室友认出他是泰莎的老板
The roommate identified him as Tessa's boss,
罗伊德·科茨曼  科茨曼保险经纪行的总裁
Lloyd Kurtzman, C.E.O. of Kurtzman Insurance Brokerage.
有前科吗
Any priors?
没犯什么大罪
Nothing major.
被投诉过几次性骚扰
He's got a couple of harassment suits,
不过他确实曾是个少年犯
but he does have a sealed juvie file.
少年犯
A juvie file?
联系马克维法官
Call Judge Markaway.
就算科茨曼小时候虐狗
If Kurtzman was torturing puppies as a kid,
我也要知道
I want to know.
英俊多金  符合泰莎的神秘男友形象
Good-looking and rich, huh? Just like Tessa's mystery man.
就像泰莎的神秘男友  他有家室了
And like Tessa's mystery man, he's married.
她那么光彩夺目
She was such a glowing presence.
让你无法抗拒
You couldn't help but notice her.
有人想杀她  真是难以想象
You know, it's hard to imagine anyone wanting to kill her.
确实如此
I'm sure it is.
你们俩亲近吗
Were the two of you close?
和我跟其他雇员一样亲近
As close as I am to any of my employees.
你上次见她是什么时候
And when was the last time that you saw her?
周五上午
Friday morning
在我们的员工会议上
at our staff meeting.
周五上午  你确定吗
Friday morning? Are you sure?
确定
Yes.
不是周五晚吗
Not friday evening?
不是
No, uh--
那你没在晚上7:45去她家吗
So you didn't go to Tessa's apartment at 7:45?
她家  没  没
Her--her apartment? No, no.
那就怪了
That's funny.
有目击者看到你那晚出现在她家
We, um, we have a witness that saw you there that night.
科茨曼先生  你周五晚在哪里
Mr. Kurtzman, where were you Friday night?
我想立刻见我的律师
I-I'd like to speak to my lawyer now.
他不肯开口
He's not talking.
我想指望他坦白是希望不大了
I guess a confession was too much to hope for.
或许能有某种说法来解释前因后果
Some story that might explain it all.
对  我们派了人手去他家和他办公室
Yeah, we've got teams at his home and his office.
搜查过后就能见分晓了
We'll know more after the search,
埃斯波西托和他妻子谈过
but Esposito talked to his wife,
她说他那晚没回家
and she said he didn't come home that night.
他工作到很晚
He was working late.
我想他当时没在工作
I'm guessing he wasn't at work.
对
No.
我在想是否还有其他受害人
I wonder if there were others
还是她是第一个
or if she was the first,
是否她的"光彩夺目"唤醒了他内心的欲望
if her "Glowing presence" awakened something inside him.
怎么了
What's wrong?
我...
It's...
我只是想起了犯罪现场
It's just that crime scene.
怎么了
What about it?
杀死泰莎的凶手心思缜密
The person that killed Tessa was meticulous,
可我们审问科茨曼时  他诚惶诚恐
but when we questioned Kurtzman, he got all flustered.
所以呢
So?
所以如果他能那么心思缜密地去杀她
So if he put that much thought into killing her,
为什么却没准备好自己的不在场证明
then why didn't he have an alibi prepared?
说不定他太过缜密
Perhaps because he was so meticulous,
没想过会被捕
he didn't expect to get caught.
什么情况
Hey. What'd you find?
还在取证阶段
Well, they're still processing,
可目前为止还没发现他家或办公室
but so far there's nothing at his house or office
有把他和凶案联系起来的证据
that connects Kurtzman to the murder.
查他的电邮了吗
Did you check his e-mails?
查了  他硬盘上没有被删除的神秘文件
Yeah. There's no mysterious deletions from his hard drive,
没异常活动
no unusual activity,
电话记录也没有可疑号码
nothing in his phone records, either.
好  这也不足为奇
Okay, well, that's not a surprise.
如果他不是初犯
I mean, if he's done this before,
就会知道如何掩盖罪证
he knows how to cover his tracks.
他的少年犯记录呢
What about his juvie record?
打过几次架  偷过一辆邻居的车
A couple of fights, stole a neighbor's car.
没有和这次相关的前科
Nothing that explains this.
所以我们现在只有她邻居的指认吗
So then all we have is the neighbor's I.D.?
这样可破不了案
That's not enough to make a case.
我可能找到了有用证据
I think I might have found something that can help,
科茨曼可能漏掉的东西
Something Kurtzman may have missed.
一只钻石耳环
A diamond earring?
沙发里找到的
We found it in the couch.
鉴证组提取不到上面的指纹
C.S.U. couldn't pull a print off it,
可你看到这图案了吗
But you see the design?
定制的  艾瑞卡·科特尼
That's custom-- Erica Courtney.
你怎么知道的
And you know this how?
我和珍妮买耳环的时候知道的
I recognized it from when Jenny and I went ring shopping.
不管怎样  我联系了展示厅
Anyway, I called up the showroom.
他们确认这是他们的产品
They confirmed it's one of theirs.
他们有销售记录吗
And do they have a record of who they sold it to?
有  我查了姓名和地址
Yeah, I ran the name and the address.
都是伪造的
They're both fake.
信用卡信息呢
What about the credit card info?
买耳环的人用的是支票  一万二
Well, buyer paid with a cashier's check. 12 grand.
所以我们也没法追查到他或者这笔钱了
So we have no way of tracing him or the payment.
对  但是商店用了数码监控
No, but the store uses digital surveillance,
他们刚刚把录影带送过来
And they just sent over the tapes.
这就是物品出售的时间点
Here's the time code for our point of sale.
这就是我们要找的人
That's our guy.
看看他的身高
Look at his height,
体型  发色
build, hair color.
他不是科茨曼
That's not Kurtzman.
他是  卡塞尔
That's... Castle.
一定还有其他的解释
There's another explanation.
比如说
Like what?
我不知道  好吗  那是其他人
I don't know, okay? It's somebody else.
某个看起来像卡塞尔的人
Someone that looks like castle.
我们在案发现场发现了他的指纹
We found his fingerprints at the crime scene.
我们在录像上看到他给被害人买珠宝
We got him on video buying jewelry for our victim.
这绝不是巧合
It can't be a coincidence.
哈维  你是说卡塞尔是凶手吗
Javi, what are you saying, that Castle's a killer?
不不不  我们谁都没这么说
Whoa, whoa, whoa. No, no, no. None of us are saying that.
他的意思就是
All he's saying is that
如果是其他人  我们会好好查的
If it were anyone else, we'd look into it.
我们可以先查他的财务信息
We can start by looking at his financials,
看看他在买下下珠宝那段时间
See if there's any unusual activity
是否有过不正常的活动
around the time of the purchase.
好吧
Fine.
但我们必须要悄悄地进行
But we do it quietly,
不能让他知道
and he never finds out about it.
你到底要干嘛
What are you doing?
哈维  有件事必须让你知道
Uh, Javi, there's something you need to know.
贝克特和卡塞尔
Beckett and Castle?
什么时候开始的
W--uh--w-when did they start?
不清楚
I'm not sure.
但我知道他们那个周末是在汉普顿一起过的
But I know they were together that weekend in the Hamptons.
她为什么不告诉我们
Why wouldn't she tell us?
我猜她是担心盖茨会发现
I guess she was afraid Gates would find out,
然后用警局的规定把卡塞尔赶走
use NYPD regs to give Castle the boot.
我本来打算谁都不告诉
I was gonna keep it a secret myself,
但是  现在看来
but, ah, under the circumstances...
一般情况下  我会为他们开心的
Normally, I'd be happy for them.
是啊
Yeah. Hey.
你不会真觉得
You don't really think
卡塞尔和这件事有关系吧
that Castle had anything to do with this, do you?
当然不会  伙计  他也是我哥们儿
No. Come on, man. He's my friend, too.
我们能做的就是证明证据是错的
The best thing we can do is try to prove this evidence wrong.
是啊
Yeah.
哈维
Hey, Javi.
等等
Wait a minute.
我是不是办了派对  结果自己忘了
Did I throw a party and forget again?
这不是派对
It's not a party.
搜查证  手套
Search warrant, gloves...
好了  伙计们
Okay, guys,
我明白  指纹那回事儿嘛
I get it-- the fingerprint thing.
对不住了  下次一定注意  你们可以撤了
I'm sorry. Lesson learned. You can all go home.
这不是开玩笑  兄弟
It's not a joke, bro.
带他到厨房
Take him to the kitchen.
厨房  我刚刚
The kitchen? I just--
贝克特  怎么回事
Beckett, what is this?
我们在泰莎的公寓找到了一件珠宝
We found a piece of jewelry in Tessa's apartment
我们追查到了给她买珠宝的男人
and we traced it back to the man that bought it for her.
就是你  卡塞尔
Castle, it was you.
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
是以12780元的支票买下的
It was purchased with a Cashier's check for $12,780.
同一天  你从账户中
Earlier that day, you withdrew the same amount of money
提取了同等额度的支票资金
from your pocket account as a cashier's check.
你查过我的财务了
You looked into my financials?
你在调查我
You're investigating me?
-卡塞尔  -凯特  这不是我
- Castle - Kate, this is not me.
我没买任何珠宝
And I didn't buy any jewelry.
我也绝没有用支票
I certainly didn't use a cashier's check.
那你就要好好解释解释了
Then you need to explain it.
这个  提款  指纹
This, the withdrawal, the fingerprint--
你得告诉我究竟是怎么回事
You need to tell me what the hell's going on.
这里
In here.
是什么
What is it?
伙计们  到底是什么
Guys, what is it?
凯特
Kate.
理查德·卡塞尔
Richard Castle,
你因涉嫌谋杀泰莎·霍顿而被捕了
You're under arrest for the murder of Tessa Horton.
转过身去
Turn around.
你有权保持沉默
You have the right to remain silent.
但你说的每一句话都将作为呈堂证供
Anything you say can and will be used against you in a court of law.
这个包是他拥有的书包套装之一
The bag is part of a set that he owns.
电线和钩子同捆绑被害人的东西
The wire and hooks are identical
是一致的
to the ones used to bind the victim.
里面还有一件衬衫
There was also a shirt inside
上面沾有血迹
that had some blood spatter on it.
实验室说与泰莎的血吻合
The lab says it's a match to tessa's.
他怎么说的
What's he saying?
他以前从来没有见过这些
That he's never seen any of it before in his life.
长官  他不会杀人的
Sir, he's not a killer.
那你对此如何解释
Then how do you explain all of this?
证据不能代表一切
The evidence isn't the whole story.
这是卡塞尔教会我的
Castle's taught me that.
虽然我一直不怎么喜欢卡塞尔先生
You know, I'm not always a fan of Mr. Castle's, Detective,
但是我也难以相信
But even I'm having trouble believing
他会做出如此穷凶极恶之事
He'd do something so heinous.
那我们怎么办
So then what do we do?
做好我们的工作
Our jobs.
检查他的电子邮件  电脑文件  通话记录
Check his e-mails, computer files, and phone records.
如果他和这个女孩有关系
If he was involved with this girl,
一定会留下记录的
There's bound to be a record.
贝克特  你去和家人谈
Beckett, you talk to the family,
看看还有谁能进入他家
See if anyone else has access to his place.
长官
Sir.
谢谢你
Thank you.
先别急着谢我  探长
Don't thank me yet, detective.
不论证据导向哪里我们都要追查下去
We're gonna follow the evidence no matter where it leads us.
你们查看卡塞尔通话记录的时候
You guys, when you look through Castle's phone records--
没事的
It's okay.
我们知道了
We know.
不到万不得已我们不会告诉盖茨
We won't tell Gates unless we have to.
你们知道了
You know?
怎么知道的
How?
你想想我们多神通广大啊  所以
Well, I mean, it-- it's us, so...
我们不说是因为清楚
We didn't say anything because we figured
这与其他人无关  但我们还是得问
it was nobody's business, but we gotta ask,
你当晚跟他在一起吗
were you with him that night?
没
No. Uh...
他
He, uh...
我应该在那儿的
I-I was supposed to be.
他母亲出了城
His, um, mom was out of town,
然后他说需要一点时间写书
And then he said that he needed time to write.
贝克特去哪了
Where's Beckett?
在这种情况下
Under the circumstances,
我觉得我来审讯最合适
I think it's best if I handle the interrogation.
拜托  警监  这太离谱了
Come on, Captain. This is insane.
我什么都没做过
I didn't do anything.
审讯还是必需的
Well, we still need to investigate,
这个你懂
and you know that,
先说说你跟被害人的关系吧
so let's start with your relationship to the victim.
好的  我跟她没关系
Okay. I didn't have one.
知不知道为什么你的指纹会出现在
Then any idea how your fingerprints ended up
犯罪现场
at the crime scene?
我们已经确认是鉴证组搞错了
Well, we went over that. C.S.U. made a mistake.
他们说没有
They say they didn't.
卡塞尔  如果你认识她
Castle, if you knew her--
我不认识她
I didn't know her.
她在跟某人交往
She was seeing someone,
她的室友形容那人又帅又多金
someone her roommate described as handsome and rich.
真是过奖了  但那人不是我
I'm flattered, but it wasn't me.
探长
Detective.
他的家人来了
His family's here.
-理查德人呢  -出什么事了
- Where's Richard? - What's going on?
上面当然有我的指纹  这是我的包
Of course it has my fingerprints on it. It's my bag.
但我没有放那些东西进去
But I didn't put that stuff in there.
那是谁做的
Then who did?
是不是科茨曼
What about Kurtzman?
我们知道当晚他在她家
We know he was at her apartment that night,
他还撒了谎
and he lied about it.
科茨曼的不在场证明成立了
Kurtzman alibied out.
什么  什么时候
What? When?
一小时之前
An hour ago.
他的律师让他配合调查了
His lawyer got him to cooperate.
-其实他是被引诱去的  -被引诱
- Turns out, he was lured there. - Lured?
泰莎发了条短信给他
By a text message Tessa sent,
只不过这不是她发的
Only it wasn't from Tessa.
用一次性手机
It was from a burner phone.
科茨曼到泰莎那儿后
When Kurtzman showed up at Tessa's,
她说她并没有发过短信
she told him that she didn't send it,
于是就让他走了
so she sent him on his way.
那他为什么要撒谎呢
Well, then why did he lie about it?
因为余下的整晚他都跟应招女在一起
Because he spent the rest of the evening with a paid companion
不想让他妻子知道
and didn't want his wife to know.
那么
So...
你呢  卡塞尔先生
What about you, Mr. Castle?
谋杀当晚你在哪里
Where were you the night of the murder?
我在家里写书
I was at home writing.
有人在那儿看见你了吗
And did anyone see you there?
没有  我
No, I was...
一个人
Alone.
声明一下
So for the record,
你说你没有不在场证明
You're saying you have no alibi.
我要见我的律师
I think I'd like my lawyer now.
太疯狂了
Well, this is madness.
这太疯狂了
This is just madness.
暂时如此  我们会查明真相
It's temporary. We just need to find out the truth.
有谁能进入你们家
Now can anyone else access your apartment?
谁还有钥匙
Does anyone have keys?
艾丽西亚  管家
Well, Alicia, the housekeeper.
但她跟了我们十五年了
Yeah, but she's been with us for 15 years.
还有安保系统
And there's a security system.
即使有人用钥匙  警报都会响
Even if someone had a key, the alarm would go off.
你们有没有注意到楼里最近
Have you noticed anyone out of the ordinary
有什么可疑人物出没  比如维修工
in the building lately-- a maintenance worker,
送货员  任何可能进去的人
delivery man, anyone that could've been casing the place?
不不  没有
No, no, no, no. Nothing.
谢谢  我留在这里
Thanks. I'll be here.
卡塞尔  不论谁在幕后操控
Castle, whoever is behind this,
不论发生什么
Whatever is going on,
我都会找出来  我保证
I will figure this out. I promise.
我知道
I know.
与此同时  有人来看你了
In the meantime, you have some visitors.
老爸
Dad.
理查德
Oh, Richard.
亲爱的
Oh, darling.
什么
What?
技术部刚刚查完卡塞尔的电脑
Tech just finished with Castle's computer.
部分数据被抹掉了  跟泰莎的一样
Parts of it had been wiped, just like Tessa's.
他们能恢复数据吗
Were they able to re-- recover anything?
他们找到一个他删除的文件
They found a file that he had deleted.
是一个故事  写如何做到完美谋杀
It was a story concept about how to commit the perfect murder.
贝克特  故事人物用奇异的犯罪现场布置
Beckett, the character gets away with it
逃脱了处罚
by staging a crime scene so bizarre,
他就躲在警察的鼻子底下逍遥法外
The cops can't see he's hiding right under their noses.
就像是在纸上的预演
It was like a-a dry run on paper,
就连被害人前额
all the way down to the weird symbol
找到的怪异符号都一样
that we found on the victim's forehead.
还从他的硬盘里发现了
We found something else on his drive.
电子邮件  几十封
E-mails... dozens of 'em,
往来于卡塞尔和被害人之间
between Castle and the victim.
贝克特
Beckett...
他们在交往
They've been having an affair.
他们大约八个星期前开始的
They started up about eight weeks ago
根据这些电子邮件显示
According to those e-mails.
卡塞尔在一次签售会后遇见了她
He met her after one of his... book signings,
然后请她去喝咖啡
and he asked her out for coffee,
那时
and that was...
那时我们才刚刚开始
That was just a couple of weeks
恋爱一个星期
after we started seeing each other.
亲爱的
Oh, sweetie.
卡塞尔告诉她不能被别人发现
He told her that he needed to keep it a secret
因为他有女朋友了
because he was with someone else.
大约一个星期前卡塞尔想要分手
And then when he tried to break it off about a week ago,
她就威胁要去告诉他的女朋友
she threatened to go and tell his girlfriend.
卡塞尔提出让她去他家
He offered to come over to her apartment
把事情说开
to talk things through,
也就是她被害的那天晚上
and that was the night of the murder.
他有杀人的动机
He had motive.
卡塞尔是怎么说的
What did Castle say when you talked to him?
他说这些电子邮件是假的
He said that the e-mails were faked.
他从没写过那个情节
He said he never wrote that story,
他说他是被陷害的
and that he was being framed.
你要是见到他你就明白了  蕾妮
You should've seen him, Lanie.
他看上去就像个小孩子  感到十分害怕
He looked like a little boy, he was so scared.
我了解他  蕾妮
I know him, Lanie.
他是个
He is...
长不大  又任性
an immature, egotistical...
以自我为中心  有时很混蛋的一个人
self-centered jackass sometimes,
但他决不会杀人
but he's not this.
你真这么觉得
Are you sure?
据说只有狗才能嗅到恐惧
They say dogs can smell fear.
但你知道吗  有的人也能
Did you know that some humans can as well?
你现在就散发着恐惧的味道
You reek of it.
泰森
Tyson.
还是叫我3XK吧
I prefer 3XK.
自从上次我把你和莱恩警探丢在汽车旅馆
How long has it been since I left you
已经过去多长时间了
and Detective Ryan in that motel room?
来人啊  快来人啊  快来救我啊
Somebody! Help! Somebody! I need some help in here!
他们听不见
They can't hear you
也看不见你
or see you.
我想这方面我做得还是挺彻底的
I'm afraid I'm much more thorough than that.
这一切都是你干的
You did this.
你杀了泰莎
You killed Tessa.
她不是我喜欢的类型  我喜欢金发的
She's not my type. I prefer blondes.
还记得吗
Remember?
大家更愿意相信
Here's a much more believable story--
是你杀了泰莎
You killed Tessa.
这情节一说就通
It practically writes itself.
毕竟  你每天都在心里为你的小说
After all, you commit murder every day in your mind
构思怎么犯罪
for your books.
不难想象你终于有一天
It's not hard to imagine that you'd eventually...
付诸实现了
cross the line.
你为什么要这么做  泰森
Why are you doing this, Tyson?
四年了  卡塞尔
Four years, Castle.
我花了四年的时间
I gave up four years of my life
来策划一场完美的人间蒸发的好戏
planning the perfect vanishing act.
这样警察就不会再去搜捕我了
So that the cops would stop looking for me,
我也就可以重新开始了
So that I could begin again,
重新开始杀人了
Could begin killing again
我就可以再一次尝到
So that I could taste that fear...
恐惧的味道
again.
我辛苦了四年
Four years.
你却毁了一切
You ruined it.
如果要想要的是报复
Well, if it's revenge you wanted,
为什么不直接杀了我
why not just kill me?
那还有什么乐子
Where's the fun in that?
不不不  毁了你比杀了你更有意思
Oh, no, no, it's more fun to destroy you.
要不你觉得我那天晚上为什么不杀了你呢
Why do you think I let you live that night in the motel?
别人都以为我喜欢的是杀人
People think it's killing that I like,
其实杀人只是一个结果
But murder's just an act.
最刺激的是你的期望  你的计划
It's all about the anticipation, the planning.
看着你和女儿散步
Watching you and your daughter taking a walk,
和贝克特做爱
You and Beckett making love...
随意出入你的家
Standing in your living room,
潜伏到你的生活中
being inside your life,
想到你的这一切都会被我毁掉
Knowing that I'm gonna take it all away from you...
这才是我喜欢的部分
that's what I like.
你是逃不掉的
You won't get away with this.
得了吧
Oh, please.
你还能做什么  你跟他们说我来过这儿
What are you gonna do, you gonna tell 'em that I came here?
你觉得他们会相信一个
You think that they're gonna
极度绝望的人的话吗
believe the lies of a desperate man?
贝克特会的
Beckett will.
即使她相信
Well, even if she does...
她也救不了你
She can't save you.
因为没有时间了
There's no time.
明天检察官就会对你提起指控
When the D.A. files charges tomorrow,
他们会把你送到扣押中心
They're gonna send you to central booking--
那里被人称为坟墓
The tombs.
那儿有我的朋友
I have people waiting...
在等着你
for you.
你连一个晚上都活不过
You will not last the night.
这是对她的惩罚
And that'll be her punishment--
相信你是无辜的
Believing that you were innocent,
却依然救不了你
and not being able to stop it.
这会让她内疚一辈子
It'll haunt her for the rest of her life.
你很幸运  因为那时你早就死了
Lucky for you... you'll be dead.
我们检查了昨天晚上的监控录像
We went through the surveillance footage from last night.
没有证据显示杰瑞·泰森昨晚出现在警局
There's no evidence that Jerry Tyson was in the station,
也没有证据显示
and there is no evidence
我们的监控系统被篡改过
that the system had been tampered with.
贝克特  我向你发誓  他昨晚来过这
Beckett, I swear to you, he was here.
-卡塞尔 -我知道  这听起来不可思议
- Castle. - No, I know. I sound crazy.
就像一个绝望的人说的绝望的话  就像
A desperate story from a desperate man, just...
就像他所期望的
just like he wanted.
你说的没错  听起来是很绝望
You're right, it does sound desperate.
但是这件事终于能讲得通了
But it's the first time that this story has made sense.
你相信我
You believe me?
我一直相信
I never stopped.
他要杀我  凯特
He's gonna kill me, Kate.
我跑不了  也躲不了
I can't run, I can't hide.
我该怎么办
What am I supposed to do?
我告诉你  是三重杀手干的
I'm telling you, it's the triple killer.
勒杀  误导  伪造证据
Strangulation, misdirects, planting evidence--
都是泰森的手法
It's Tyson's M.O.
3XK通常针对多个被害人  且都为女性从来没有男性
3XK targeted multiple victims, always women, never men.
这次为什么不同
So why the change?
报仇  这是唯一能解释一切的答案
Revenge. That's the only thing that explains everything.
不  不是一切  这解释不了卡塞尔的视频
No, not everything. Not that video of Castle.
事实上  有可能
Yeah, actually, it might.
泰森在之前的案子里有过类似的作法
Tyson did something similar in the Russo case.
他曾用替身使我们做出错误判断
He used a double for the cameras to throw us off.
长官  地检官已经递交了诉讼
Sir, the D.A. has already filed charges.
他们今天就会把他送去扣押中心
They're gonna send him to Central Booking today.
我们定能证明他的阴谋  但我们需要时间
We know that we can prove this. We just need more time.
你要地检办公室做什么
You want the D.A.'s office to do what?
我们只是要求能暂缓指控以待案情明朗
All we're asking for is a delay until we can sort all this out.
不  你们要求的是对杀人嫌犯的
No, what you're asking for is preferential treatment
特殊优待
for a murder suspect.
你们要侦破案子
You want to sort this out,
等他被传讯后你们再侦破
you sort it out after he's arraigned.
不  我想你没明白
No, I don't think you understand.
他会死在里面  根本不会有之后
There's not gonna be an after.
如果你担心的是他的安全问题
If it's his safety you're concerned about,
我们会对他进行保护性监禁
we're prepared to put him in protective custody.
你知道你们要对付的人是谁吗
Do you have any idea who you're dealing with?
你知道杰瑞·泰森
Do you even know what Jerry Tyson
能做出什么事吗
has proven himself capable of?
你以为他在你们手里逃脱后
Who do you think met with the families of his victims
是谁安慰了被害人的家属
and held their hands
是谁握着他们的手  探长
when he slipped through your fingers, detective?
我很清楚3XK能做出什么事
I'm very aware of what 3XK is capable of.
那你应该明白你们的保护性监禁
Then you should know that your protective custody
根本没用
isn't worth a damn.
他要是想杀卡塞尔  他总会想到办法的
If he wants to kill Castle, he's gonna find a way to do it.
盖茨警监  除了杀人嫌犯
Captain Gates, aside from your
毫无根据的口供之外
unsubstantiated claim from a murder suspect,
你能不能向地检提供一点点
can you offer the D.A.'s office one shred of evidence
能表明3XK涉案的证据
of 3XK's inolvement?
暂时不能
Not at this time.
那没什么好说的了
Then we're done here.
我在扣押中心待过
I've spent some time in Central.
真心是个坟墓
I've seen the tombs,
那里面死人是经常的事
the way they stack bodies in those cells.
要是有人悬赏卡塞尔的人头
If there's a bounty on Castle's head,
保护性监禁根本就没用
protective custody ain't gonna do jack.
那还是假设泰森买通了罪犯
That's assuming Tyson paid off a prisoner.
更可怕的是买通了守卫
It could be a guard.
那我们就没办法在那儿保护他
So we can't protect him, not there.
我们必须阻止转送
We have to stop that transfer.
我们得找到3XK涉案的证据
We need evidence that 3XK was involved.
是啊  但我们没有线索
Yeah, but we got nothing to go on.
要实现这一切  他得进入卡塞尔的家
Okay, to pull this off, he needed access to Castle's loft.
派人去他家  把那里翻个遍
So get teams over there and tear that place apart.
给我找指纹  窃听器
Find me a fingerprint, a hidden microphone,
坏了的窗栓  任何能说明他在场的东西
a broken window jamb, anything that puts him there.
泰莎有约会对象  如果不是卡塞尔
Tessa was seeing someone. If it wasn't Castle...
那就可能是泰森
Then maybe it was Tyson.
去她的办公室
Hit her office.
查文件  日程安排  客户名单
Look for files, schedules, client lists.
肯定有东西能和他联系起来
There's gotta be something that ties back to him.
我刚听完卡塞尔家那组的报告
I just heard from the team at Castle's loft.
没发现什么
Nothing yet.
真会像泰森说的那样吗
So it's gonna happen just like Tyson said, huh?
我没办法及时救下他
I'm not gonna be able to save him in time.
我们还没查完呢
Well, we're not done yet.
看守管得严吗
How secure is holding?
什么  你可不能打这个主意
What? Whoa. You're not even thinking about that.
这事关他的性命  不能让他们带走他
We're talking about his life. We can't let them take him.
你疯了吗  这不可能的
Are you crazy? It would never work.
你根本就躲不过看守
You'll never even get out of holding.
泰森就做到过
Tyson did it.
那是因为没人注意他
Because nobody was looking for him.
他周密计划了好几个星期  甚至更久
He had weeks to plan it, maybe even longer. Y--
我知道你对他的感情
I know how you feel about the guy.
我也爱他
I love him, too.
但我们无能为力
But there's nothing we can do.
他们来了
They're here.
这可没有上次在你家
This is so much less fun
那么有意思了
than the other night at your place.
还记得你第一次拷上我吗
Do you remember the first time you handcuffed me?
我们在纽约公共图书馆
We were at the New York Public Library.
还记得你不能阻止我
Remember how angry you were
调查案子时  你有多生气吗
that I wouldn't stop investigating that case?
是啊  我记得
Yeah, I remember.
我真想回到那个时候
What I wouldn't give to be there now.
卡塞尔
Castle...
案子还没结呢
This isn't over.
我保证  我会救你出来
I promise you, I will get you out.
没关系
It's okay.
不管发生什么
Whatever happens,
都没关系
It's okay.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
没必要抱歉  我不需要抱歉
Don't be sorry. I don't need sorry.
我要把那混蛋找出来
I need to find this son of a bitch
送他归西
and put him in the ground.
贝克特探长
Detective Beckett.
怎么了
What?
我们奉命来此转押一人去扣押中心
We're here to transport one of yours to Central--
叫理查德·卡塞尔
A, uh, Richard Castle?
对  我是在看转押书...
Yes, I'm looking at the transfer...
不  文件上写着警徽号为871324
No, the paper work said the bedge number was 871324.
扣押中心说车没有抵达
The Central Booking said it never arraived,
他们也不知道车在哪里
they don't know where the hell it is.
好的
Right. OK.
文件上的警徽编号不存在
The badge numbers on the paperwork don't exit.
他们是假冒的
They were imposters.
一定是泰森干的  他设计好的
It's gotta be Tyson. He sets this up.
他不会让别人杀卡塞尔的
He isn't gonna have Castle killed.
他想亲手杀死他
He's gonna kill him himself.
地方检察官认为这是越狱
Well, the D.A. is calling it a prisoner escape.
他们签发了一张全面通缉令
They've issued an A.P.B
不准我把他捞出来
and restricted me to get the man.
什么  他们认为是卡塞尔干的吗
What? They think Castle did this?
按他们的考虑
As far as their concern,
他结交甚广  熟悉流程
he's well connected, knows our procedure,
还有大量的可用资源
and has substantial resources.
太荒谬了
That's ridiculous.
你们俩继续查泰森
You two keep working the Tyson angle.
我来处理这个
I've got this.
资源
Resources.
你能相信吗
Can you believe that?
卡塞尔可能已经被连环杀手
Branding Castle a fugitive
劫持了  他们还把他当逃犯
when he's probably being held captive by a serial killer?
我们接下来该
So what's our next...
干什么
move?
感谢上帝  你没事
Oh, thank God you're okay.
感谢上帝你听懂我说的话了
Thank God you understood my message.
我第一次拷上你
The first time that I cuffed you--
你愿付出一切回到那
What you wouldn't give to be back there now.
-来吧  -好
- Come on. - Yeah.
我知道  我没法给你打电话
I knew I couldn't call once I left.
卡塞尔你怎么办到的  怎么逃出来的
Castle, how did you do it? How did you escape?
-我的律师很厉害  -得了吧
- I've got a great lawyer. - Come on.
有人欠我人情  你知道的越少越好
Someone owned me a favor. The less you know, the better.
但好消息是  我还活着
But the good news is, I'm still alive.
地方检察官通告说你是逃犯了
The D.A. has branded you a fugitive.
纽约的所有警察都在找你
Every cop in New York is looking for you.
五点钟的新闻过后
Yes, well, they won't be the only ones
找我的就不只是警察了
after the 5:00 news.
他们监视着我的电话  房子和账户
And by now they've tagged my phone, my house, my accounts.
我逃不了多久  我们得加紧行动
I'm not gonna last long out here. We have to act quickly.
我安排人去你家查找泰森留下的蛛丝马迹了
I've got teams at your place looking for any trace of Tyson.
莱恩在彻查泰莎办公室的文件
Ryan is wading through paperwork at Tessa's office
看能不能查出什么联系来
to see if there's a connection.
可能得查几周时间  我有个更快的办法
Well, that could take weeks. I think I got something better.
在牢房里  我一直在想
Sitting in holding, I kept thinking,
他怎么做到的
how could he possibly pull this off?
他怎么能弄到我去买耳坠的录像
How could he get video of me buying those earrings?
后来我突然想到了
And then it hit me...
《百老汇选角》
"Broadway Casting"?
你想找人演个角色  登广告
You want someone to play a role, you cast it.
看看这个  四个月前的广告
Look at this notice from four months ago
一家明星替身公司登的
by a celebrity lookalike firm.
私人书会派对
"A private book club party."
看他们都要谁
Look who they're looking for.
詹姆斯·帕特森[《桃色通缉令》作者]
"James Patterson,
史蒂芬·金[《肖申克的救赎》作者]
Stephen King,
J.K.罗琳[《哈利波特》作者]
J.K. Rowling"...
还有  我
And... me.
对  是我们登的这条广告
Yeah, we placed that ad.
把几个人的头像发到客户的邮箱里
Sent a couple of headshots over to the client's P.O. Box,
就没信儿了
but never heard back.
能把地址给我吗
Uh, could I get the address?
当然
Sure.
你发过理查德·卡塞尔替身的照片吗
And did you send over any Richard Castles?
我查查
Let me check.
只有一个
Just one.
太好了  我们也需要他的资料
Great. We'll need his information as well.
好的  谢谢
Okay, thanks.
这家公司邮寄头像照片的收信邮箱
So the P.O. Box the agency sent the headshots to
是用现金租来的  只租了一个月
was paid for in cash and rented for a month.
邮箱主人没有转寄地址
The owners gave no forwarding address.
死胡同
It's a dead end.
泰森或许是条死胡同
Well, Tyson might be a dead end,
但理查德·卡塞尔可不是
but Richard Castle isn't.
看啊  那就是我
Look, it's me.
没错  有时会有人来找我
Yeah, people come up sometimes,
让我给你的书签名
asking me to sign your books.
因此我觉得我应该去报名
So I figured I'd submit.
从没听到回信
I never heard back.
这么近距离的看
You know, uh, now that I'm up close,
还真没觉得像
I really don't see it.
那么
Uh... so, uh,
这个是你吗
I-is this you?
是啊
Yeah.
那是个商场安保用的真人秀
That was for a reality show on store security.
挺奇怪的  他们让我去买耳坠
It was an odd gig. They sent me in to buy earrings.
有这个人的事吗
And was this man involved somehow?
好像是那个真人秀的制片人
He looks a little like the show's producer.
你不会刚好有他的联系方式吧
You wouldn't happen to have his contact information, would you?
什么叫他和你在一起
What do you mean, he's with you?
他怎么逃出来的
How did he escape?
埃斯波  现在别问  我需要一个地址
Espo, not now. I need an address.
好吧  制作人的地址也是假的
All right, the address for the show's producer is another dead PO box
电话号码也是空号
and the phone number's defunct.
支付工资的那张支票呢
Okay, what about his paycheck?
我问过银行了
Well, I talked to the bank,
支票关联的账户已经销户了
and the corporate account that cut the check is closed.
账户联系人
And the corporate contact,
约瑟夫·范启尔也不存在
Joseph Vacher, well, doesn't seem to exist.
不  这个人存在  至少存在过
Yeah, he exists, all right. Or at least he used to.
约瑟夫·范启尔是十九世纪晚期的
Joseph Vacher is a famous French serial killer
一位著名的法国连环杀手
from the late 1800s.
这么说他还有点幽默感
So he's got a sense of humor.
那个公司账户
Have any other checks been written
还开出过支票吗
from that corporate account?
没错  给的是
Yeah, cut to a...
科茨曼保险公司
Kurtzman Insurance.
泰莎在那里工作
Tessa worked for them.
她的公司档案里没提到范启尔
So there's no mention of Vacher in her policy files...
不过  在她的日历上
but there was an entry in her calendar.
在这儿了
Yeah, here it is.
六周前  和一个叫J.V.的人见面
Six weeks ago-- site visit with a J.V.
就是他  肯定是
Well, that's him. It has to be.
她有没有写别的信息
Did she write anything else with it--
比如电话号码  电子邮件  地址等
a phone number, e-mails, an address?
没有号码  不过有个地址
No phone number, but there is an address.
或许就是他们见面进行考察的地址
Maybe where they went for the site visit.
就在北曼哈顿
Looks like it's in northern Manhattan
大桥附近
near the bridge.
卡塞尔  他在假扮大楼所有者
Castle, he was posing as a building owner
找保险
looking for insurance.
很有可能他找到了一栋空大楼
He probably found an empty property.
值得一查
Could be worth a look.
凯文  带埃斯波到那个地址找我们
Kev, hook up with Espo and meet us there.
没问题
You got it.
有人看了新闻认出我了  快走
Someone saw the news. We gotta go.
户主说这楼没人用
Owner says it's unoccupied.
一年没有租出去过了
Hasn't been a tenant for nearly a year.
那是谁在上面
Then who's up there?
可能有人  也可能就是一盏亮着的灯
Could be someone or it could be just a light.
-看到那个动静没  -好了大伙  行动吧
- Did you just see that? - All right, guys. Let's move. Come on.
没人
It was nothing.
床单罢了
Just a sheet.
大伙
You guys.
过来看
Over here.
他在卡塞尔的公寓得到他的指纹后
Once he'd obtained Castle's print from his loft,
用粘合剂和生胶浆
he used a binding agent and some rubber cement
做了一个指纹乳胶手模
to build a latex model of his fingerprint.
监视照片
Surveillance photos,
卡塞尔家的装修招工广告
architectural plans for Castle's loft...
还有辖区地图
A precinct map,
上面标记了所有监控摄像头的位置
including the locations of all of our video cameras--
他精心安排了这一切
He orchestrated everything right down to the last detail.
他甚至把科茨曼也拉下水
He even implicated Kurtzman
让这事看着像是卡塞尔为了隐藏行踪而干的
to make it look like Castle was covering his tracks.
我不明白
I don't get it.
他干嘛费这么大劲陷害你
Why go through all this just to set you up?
因为一死了之太便宜我了
Because death only takes a moment.
精心准备一出大案  是他的癖好
The preparation and pageantry, that's what he loves.
好吧  卡塞尔先生
Well, Mr. Castle,
看来你已经摆脱嫌疑了
it looks like you're off the hook.
我已经跟地方检察官说过了
I've spoken to the D.A.,
他们会撤销所有指控
and they'll be dropping all charges.
谢谢长官
Thank you, sir.
谋杀指控是没了
For this, at least.
但你逃脱监管这条罪名还在
There's still the matter of your escape from custody.
不过鉴于目前情况
However, under the circumstances,
我想你应该能讨个已服刑期
I'm pretty sure you can negotiate down to time served.
警探  你先把他带回警局
Uh, detective, why don't you take him down to the station,
把文件都填好
start the paperwork?
战术小组搜查了整栋楼
So the tactical team searched the whole building.
没找到他
No sign of him.
等鉴证组取完证据
When C.S.U. finishes,
把东西都归回原位  将这栋楼监视起来
fall back and put the building under surveillance.
如果他已经看到我们  不会回来了怎么办
What if he's already seen us and he doesn't come back?
整座城里的警察都在找他
Every cop in this city is looking for him.
他跑不了多远
He won't get far.
你没事吧
You okay?
嗯
Yeah.
能找到泰森的那些东西...
Just finding that stuff of Tyson's...
挺走运的
It seems lucky.
有时一点运气就足够逆转一切了
Yeah, well, sometimes luck is all you need.
现在他躲不了了  我们会找到他的
He can't hide now. We'll find him.
谢谢你
Thank you.
谢什么
For what?
谢谢你相信我
Believing in me.
鉴于我的名声  还有我的过去...
I mean, given my reputation, my history...
你看到那些邮件后
when you saw those e-mails,
还会相信我  实在不容易
it would've been real easy not to.
咱俩之间的事时候什么时候容易过了
Yeah, well, things have never been easy between you and me.
或许这就是我们值得
Maybe that's what makes it all worth--
是泰森  卡塞尔  趴下
It's Tyson. Castle, get down!
来啊  凯特  过来
Come here, Kate. Come here.
卡塞尔
Castle!
你的女人在我手里
I got your girl!
看到了吗
Are you watching?
我要让你看着这一切
I want you to see this.
你以为我会这么容易就让你逃脱吗
You think that I'd let you live after everything you've done?
卡塞尔
Castle!
来啊  好好看着
Come on. I want you to watch.
我要让你亲眼看着我杀掉她
I want you to watch as I take her life.
在这儿呢
Over here.
河水颜色太暗了  暂时还没发现目标
The water's pretty murky. Haven't seen anything yet.
他们还是没找到尸体
They still haven't found the body.
他们找不到的
They won't.
他没死
He's not dead.
卡塞尔  你说什么呢
Castle, what are you saying?
整件事根本就不是针对我
This was never about me.
是他为了自己而策划的
This was about him.
记得死者笔记本里的名字缩写吗
Those initials in her date book?
他不会那么粗心的
He's not that careless.
是他希望我们能找到那栋大楼
He wanted us to find that place.
然后让我们来这座桥
He wanted us on this bridge.
泰莎的谋杀案  还有陷害
Tessa's murder, the frame up--
所有这一切都是为了让我们来这
all of it was to get us here so we could help him do
帮他达到他自己无法完成的目的
what he couldn't do for himself--
彻底消失  以便日后再动手杀人
disappear so he can start killing again.
你觉得这些都是他计划好的
You think he planned this?
通缉犯怎样才能让自己不被继续通缉
How does a wanted man stop being wanted?
只有制造一起大案  让自己的死亡变得人尽皆知
It has to be public and it has to be final.
你知不知道这听起来多不靠谱
Do you know how crazy that sounds?
现在没有人会再通缉他了
No one's gonna be looking for him anymore.
你朝他开了枪
You shot him.
他死了  都结束了
He's dead. It's over.
暂时结束而已
For now.